Preliminary Guide to the North American Conference on British Studies records, 1949-2015 MS2187
Special Collections Research Center, The George Washington University
North American Conference on British Studies records
1949-2015
1968-2011
Special Collections Research Center, The George Washington University
Harris, Barbara J. (Barbara Jean)
North American Conference on British Studies
MS2187
32 Linear Feet 37 document boxes and 62 digital objects
This collection contains records, correspondence, meetings minutes, reports and memorandum pertaining to the North American Conference on British Studies from 1949-2015.
Restrictions on Access
This collection is open for research.
Acquisition Information
Orignal donation in 2000 by the North American Conference on Britsh Studies. Subsequent donations by individual members of the organization have been added.
Historical or Biographical Note
The North American Conference on British Studies (NACBS) is a scholarly society dedicated to all aspects of the study of British civilization. The NACBS sponsors a scholarly journal (and other, online publications), an annual conference, as well as several academic prizes, graduate fellowships, and undergraduate essay contests. While the largest single group of its members teach British history in colleges and universities in the United States and Canada, the NACBS has significant representation among specialists in literature, art history, politics, law, sociology, and economics. Its membership also includes many teachers at universities in countries outside North America, secondary school teachers, and independent scholars.
Founded in 1950, the NACBS was known in its early years simply as the Conference on British Studies(CBS). The conference became affiliated with the American Historical Association(AHA) in 1952, and was incorporated under the laws of the State of New York in 1965. It adopted its current name in 1980. The NACBS is recognized by the Internal Revenue Service as a tax-exempt organization and may accept gifts to endowment or for other purposes. The Conference is the principal scholarly organization in North America in the field of British studies. It has close ties with the Institute of Historical Research at the University of London, the Royal Historical Society, the Historical Association of Great Britain, and other learned societies, libraries, and institutions.
Collection Scope and Content
This collection contains records, correspondence, meetings minutes, reports and memorandum pertaining to the North American Conference on British Studies from 1949-2015 with the bulk of the records dating 1968-2011.
These records document the scholarship and award-granting activities.
This collection is not fully processed. Much of the material arrived loose and has been foldered into broad topics. It is available for use, but may require more additional research time to understand the order. Please contact Special Collections for more information.
Collection Organization
Organized into six series: Original donations, Executive Secretary records, President's records, Records of Susan Groag Bell, Recores of Linda Levy Peck, and Records of Dane Kennedy.
Great Britain; North America; Great Britain -- History
- Original donations, 1949-2014; 1968-2007; Series 1; 25.5 Linear Feet
  Arrangement note
  This series is arranged alphabetically. The folder list is actually put together from various donations and thus the alpahbetical list repeats. To ensure you have seen all useful materials read the entire list.
  Scope and Contents note
  This series contains records, correspondence, meetings minutes, reports and memorandum pertaining to the North American Conference on British Studies from 1949-2014. These records document the scholarship and award-granting activities.
  This series is not processed. All the material arrived loose and has been foldered into broad topics. It is available for use, but may require more additional research time to understand the order. Please contact Special Collections for more information.
  This series constitutes all donations made prior to April 2010.
  - Correspondence: Stansky, 1968-1967 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence: Stansky, 1965-1980 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence: Stansky, 1970-1972 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence: Stansky, 1968-1972 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence: Stansky, 1968-1981 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence: Stansky, 1972 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence: Stansky, 1969-1974 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence: Stansky, 1970-1978 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Correspondence: Stansky, 1972-1980 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Correspondence: Stansky, 1967-1977 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Correspondence: miscellaneous, 1967-1980 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Correspondence: miscellaneous, 1981-1983 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Meeting minutes, 1953-1982 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Meeting minutes, 1951-1985 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Meeting minutes, 1968-1976 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Correspondence: Abbott, 1968 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Correspondence: Akenson, 1968-1975 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Correspondence: Ackerman, 1969-1973 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Correspondence: Stansky, 1972-1975 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Correspondence: Stansky, 1972-1981 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Correspondence: Baxter, 1968-1969 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Correspondence: Baylen, 1968 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Correspondence: Baylen, 1968 (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Clippings and correspondence, 1971-1973 (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Correspondence: Bellot/Stansky, 1968-1978 (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - Correspondence/article Blanco, 1971 (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - Correspondence, reports, 1969 (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - Studies, 1967-1986 (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - Correspondence: studies, 1975-1976 (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - Correspondence: research project, 1968-1973 (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - Rocky Mountain Conference, 1974 (Box 1, Folder 31)
  - Publications Committee, 1965-1968 (Box 1, Folder 32)
  - Publications Committee reports, 1970-1978 (Box 1, Folder 33)
  - Publications Committee contracts, 1968-1978 (Box 1, Folder 34)
  - Correspondence: Publication Committee, 1968-1978 (Box 1, Folder 35)
  - Cambridge University Press, 1969-1974 (Box 1, Folder 36)
  - Correspondence/Reports, 1986-1987 (Box 1, Folder 37)
  - Correspondence: archive transfers, 1988-1993 (Box 1, Folder 38)
  - Prize citations, 1987 (Box 1, Folder 39)
  - Correspondence with other organizations, 1987-1988 (Box 1, Folder 40)
  - Correspondence: Publications Committee, 1985-1988 (Box 1, Folder 41)
  - Correspondence: British Studies Intelligencer, 1985-1987 (Box 1, Folder 42)
  - Correspondence: visitors programs, 1985-1988 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence: American friends, 1985-1988 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence: dissertation fellowship, 1986-1988 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence: Journal of British Studies contract, 1985-1987 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence: Albion, 1987-1988 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence: Nominating Committee and elections, undated (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence, reports, 1988 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Dissertation awards, 1982-1988 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - AHA meeting, 1986 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - British Embassy, 1987-1985 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Council meeting, 1986 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Council meeting: Portland, 1987 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Council meeting: Philadelphia, 1988 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Council meeting: Chicago, 1989 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Council meeting: New Orleans, 1990 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Council meeting: San Jose, 1991 (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Correspondence: Historical Association, 1984-1989 (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Executive Secretary: special bulletins, 1980-1989 (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - Correspondence: immediate past president, 1989-1992 (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - Correspondence: president's file, 1987-1989 (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - Nomiations for conference, 1991 (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - Correspondence: Webb, 1987-1991 (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - Correspondence: Schwoerer as Vice President, 1985-1987 (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - Correspondence: Executive Secretary, 1982 (Box 2, Folder 24)
  - Executive Secretaryship/Committee Meeting, 1974-1975 (Box 2, Folder 25)
  - Correspondence: Appeal for endoewment fund giving, 1990-1991 (Box 2, Folder 26)
  - Records: Endowment fund, gifts and pledges, 1989-1992 (Box 2, Folder 27)
  - Correspondence: Endowment fundraising, 1989-1991 (Box 2, Folder 28)
  - Correspondence: Endowment fundraising, 1988-1989 (Box 2, Folder 29)
  - Journals/Correspondence: Basil Blackwell, Inc., 1987-1990 (Box 2, Folder 30)
  - Correspondence: Biography Series, 1978-1989 (Box 2, Folder 31)
  - By-Laws, 1982-1990 (Box 2, Folder 32)
  - Correspondence: council nominations for keynote speaker, 1988 (Box 2, Folder 33)
  - Correspondence: British Embassy, 1989-1991 (Box 2, Folder 34)
  - Papers/Correspondence: AHA and CBS Session, 1977-1978 (Box 2, Folder 35)
  - Papers/Correspondence: Institute of Historical Research, 1983-1990 (Box 2, Folder 36)
  - Correspondence: prize announcements for Mid Atlantic Conference, 1983-1985 (Box 2, Folder 37)
  - North American Conference- Mid Atlantic Region, 1979-1980 (Box 2, Folder 38)
  - North American Conference- Mid Atlantic Region, undated (Box 2, Folder 39)
  - Anglo-American Meetings, 1983-1986 (Box 2, Folder 40)
  - Conference on British Studies: Mid-Atlantic Region, 1976-1980 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Conference on British Studies: Mid-Atlantic Region, 1996-1980 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence: John Ben Snow Prize, 1989-1991 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence: committees, 1984 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Report of the Advisory Committee on Resources and Planning, 1990 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Statement of cash receipts and disbursements, 1991-1993 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence: miscellaneous, 1991-1992 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Vancouver meeting, 1994 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Correspondence: miscellaneous, 1987-1992 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Correspondence: British Council, 1982-1993 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Correspondence: British Studies Intelligencer, 1989-1993 (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Correspondence: Learned societies, 1990-1992 (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Correspondence: Institude of Historical Research, 1992 (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - Correspondence: Love Prize, 1985-1988 (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - Correspondence: council meeting Boulder, Colorado, 1992 (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - Correspondence: Regionals, 1989-1991 (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - Correspondence: Brad C. Prize, 1989-1992 (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - Correspondence: miscellaneous conferences, 1988-1994 (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - By-Laws, 1982-1992 (Box 3, Folder 19)
  - Correspondence: West Kent Archive, 1990-1991 (Box 3, Folder 20)
  - Correspondence: travel reimbursement, 1992 (Box 3, Folder 21)
  - Correspondence: nominating committee, 1978-1981 (Box 3, Folder 22)
  - Southern C.B.S., Memphis, 1982 (Box 3, Folder 23)
  - Correspondence: miscellaneous, 1982-1983 (Box 3, Folder 24)
  - Correspondence: Peck, Schwoerer, 1983-1986 (Box 3, Folder 25)
  - Correspondence: Schwoerer files, 1983 (Box 3, Folder 26)
  - Correspondence: Schwoerer files, executive secretary, 1983-1984 (Box 3, Folder 27)
  - Correspondence: Schwoerer files, British Embassy, undated (Box 3, Folder 28)
  - Correspondence: Executive Secretary, 1988-1991 (Box 3, Folder 29)
  - Correspondence: Programs, 1989 (Box 3, Folder 30)
  - Correspondence: committees, 1981-1990 (Box 3, Folder 31)
  - Correspondence: Executive Committee, 1989-1990 (Box 3, Folder 32)
  - Correspondence, meeting minutes, 1983-1990 (Box 3, Folder 33)
  - Correspondence: tax exempt status, 1990 (Box 3, Folder 34)
  - Treasurer, 1987-1991 (Box 3, Folder 35)
  - Treasurer materials, 1989 (Box 3, Folder 36)
  - Conference proposal, undated (Box 3, Folder 37)
  - Toronto conference, 1984 (Box 3, Folder 38)
  - Correspondence: Schwoerer's file, Executive Secretary, 1985-1986 (Box 3, Folder 39)
  - NACBS membership list, 1987 (Box 3, Folder 40)
  - Correspondence: Schwoerer's file, complaints/inquiries, 1983-1989 (Box 3, Folder 41)
  - Correspondence: Schwoerer's file, prize inquiries, 1983-1985 (Box 3, Folder 42)
  - Correspondence: Schwoerer's file, regional programs, undated (Box 3, Folder 43)
  - Correspondence: miscellaneous, 1982-1983 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence: miscellaneous, 1984 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Papers, notes: miscellaneous, 1984 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence: miscellaneous, 1984-1985 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence: committees, 1987-1989 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence: Hollister, 1983-1988 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence: A.H.A. San Francisco meeting, 1990 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Council agenda: New Orleans, 1990 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Correspondence: New Orleans meeting, 1990 (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Correspondence: A.H.A. New York, 1991 (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Correspondence: Chicago meeting, undated (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - Correspondence, minutes: Chicago council meeting, 1989 (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - Correspondence: Philiadelphia meeting, 1988 (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - Correspondence: Portland meeting, 1985-1987 (Box 4, Folder 14)
  - Correspondence: miscellaneous, 1987-1988 (Box 4, Folder 15)
  - Correspondence: Portland meeting, 1987 (Box 4, Folder 16)
  - Minutes, 1985-1991 (Box 4, Folder 17)
  - Correspondence: New York, 10/31/1987 (Box 4, Folder 18)
  - Correspondence: Webb, undated (Box 4, Folder 19)
  - Correspondence: American Historical Association, 1988-1989 (Box 4, Folder 20)
  - Correspondence: American Council of Learned Societies(ACLS), 1989-1991 (Box 4, Folder 21)
  - Correspondence: University of Chicago Press, JBS, 1989-1990 (Box 4, Folder 22)
  - Minutes, correspondence: American Friends of the Institute of Historical Research, 1989-1990 (Box 4, Folder 23)
  - Journal of British Studies market report, 1988-1990 (Box 4, Folder 24)
  - Correspondence: Regional Conferences, 1988-1991 (Box 4, Folder 25)
  - Correspondence, miscellaneous materials: affiliates, 1989 (Box 4, Folder 26)
  - Correspondence, journals, reports: Journal of British Studies(JBS), 1984-1990 (Box 4, Folder 27)
  - Correspondence: Journal of British Studies(JBS), 1985-1989 (Box 4, Folder 28)
  - Correspondence: Albion, 1987-1990 (Box 4, Folder 29)
  - Committees, general, 1988-1994 (Box 4, Folder 30)
  - Clipping: New York Times article, 1988 (Box 4, Folder 31)
  - Correspondence: Executive Committee, 1987-1990 (Box 4, Folder 32)
  - NACBS council materials, 1989-1991 (Box 4, Folder 33)
  - Membership, undated (Box 4, Folder 34)
  - Correspondence: BIUS(British Institute of the United States), E-SU(English speaking union), 1988-1989 (Box 4, Folder 35)
  - Correspondence: British Studies Intelligencer, 1989-1990 (Box 4, Folder 36)
  - IRS: Financial materials, 1990 (Box 4, Folder 37)
  - Correspondence: Treasurer, 1988-1991 (Box 4, Folder 38)
  - Correspondence: Dissertation fellowship, 1989-1991 (Box 4, Folder 39)
  - Correspondence: Publications committee, 1989-1991 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Snow memorial trust, 1989-1991 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Nominations committee, 1988-1990 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Program committee, 1988-1991 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - New fellowship materials, 1989-1990 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence: Huntington fellowship, 1989-1990 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence: prize committees, 1988-1991 (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Prize committees, 1987-1988 (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - Memorandum, correspondence: regional conferences, 1986-1988 (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - Duties of NACBS officers, 1987-1988 (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - Annual NACBS meeting, 1987-1988 (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - Correspondence: annual meetings, 1986-1988 (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - Correspondence: AHA, 1987-1988 (Box 5, Folder 13)
  - Membership fundraising, 1987-1988 (Box 5, Folder 14)
  - Intelligencer, publications, 1987-1988 (Box 5, Folder 15)
  - Subscription forms, dues, 1990 (Box 5, Folder 16)
  - Subscription forms, dues, 1990 (Box 5, Folder 17)
  - Subscription forms, dues, 1990 (Box 5, Folder 18)
  - Subscription forms, dues, 1990 (Box 5, Folder 19)
  - Subscription forms, dues, 1990 (Box 5, Folder 20)
  - Subscription forms, dues, 1990 (Box 5, Folder 21)
  - Subscription forms, dues, 1990 (Box 5, Folder 22)
  - Subscription forms, dues, 1990 (Box 5, Folder 23)
  - Correspondence: manuscripts, 1971-1982 (Box 5, Folder 24)
  - Correspondence: Mckenna, 1968-1973 (Box 5, Folder 25)
  - British history manuscript, 1977-1980 (Box 5, Folder 26)
  - Correspondence: JBS, 1973-1983 (Box 5, Folder 27)
  - Minutes, correspondence: miscellaneous, 1982-1983 (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Minutes, bulletin, correspondence, 1982-1984 (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence: planning, undated (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Philadelphia meeting arrangements, 1988 (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Philadelphia costs, 1988-1989 (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Cincinnati, costs, 1988-1989 (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - Naylor file: member information, 1984 (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence: miscellaneous, undated (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - Snow foundation, 1989-1990 (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - Florence Savings Bank, 1988-1991 (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - British Council book prize, 1989 (Box 6, Folder 11)
  - Correspondence: stationery, 1988-1990 (Box 6, Folder 12)
  - Subsciption forms, dues, 1990 (Box 6, Folder 13)
  - Correspondence: JBS, 1988-1990 (Box 6, Folder 14)
  - Albion solicitations, 1988 (Box 6, Folder 15)
  - Correspondence: national mailings, 1988-1989 (Box 6, Folder 16)
  - Correspondence: John Naylor, 1988 (Box 6, Folder 17)
  - Meeting minutes, 1987-1991 (Box 6, Folder 18)
  - British Council: travel, 1990-1991 (Box 6, Folder 19)
  - Correspondence: Stansky, undated (Box 6, Folder 20)
  - Regional conferences, 1983-1985 (Box 6, Folder 21)
  - Visiting scholars program, 1984-1985 (Box 6, Folder 22)
  - Correspondence: Stanksy, 1970-1983 (Box 6, Folder 23)
  - Correspondence: Cline, Morel, 1981-1983 (Box 6, Folder 24)
  - Correspondence: Havighurst, Massingham Amhurst College, 1972-1979 (Box 6, Folder 25)
  - Correspondence: Stansky, undated (Box 6, Folder 26)
  - Correspondence: as president, 1974-1978 (Box 6, Folder 27)
  - Correspondence: as president, 1975-1978 (Box 6, Folder 28)
  - Archives of British History and Culture, 1966-1967 (Box 6, Folder 29)
  - Current research in British studies, 1975 (Box 6, Folder 30)
  - By-laws, 1982 (Box 6, Folder 31)
  - Editor of JBS, 1977-1978 (Box 6, Folder 32)
  - Quinquemnial Book prize, 1975-1976 (Box 6, Folder 33)
  - Correspondence: Monographs, 1975-1977 (Box 6, Folder 34)
  - Correspondence: JBS, 1972-1978 (Box 6, Folder 35)
  - Minutes, correspondence: Publications committee, 1969-1978 (Box 6, Folder 36)
  - Correspondence: Greaves, 1970 (Box 6, Folder 37)
  - Correspondence: Ferguson, 1968-1969 (Box 6, Folder 38)
  - Correspondence: Grifin, 1969-1970 (Box 6, Folder 39)
  - Correspondence: Greene, 1974 (Box 6, Folder 40)
  - Correspondence: Grugel, 1973 (Box 6, Folder 41)
  - Correspondence: Jordan, 1974-1975 (Box 6, Folder 42)
  - Correspondence: Jones, 1968-1972 (Box 6, Folder 43)
  - Correspondence: Huch, 1971-1973 (Box 6, Folder 44)
  - Correspondence: Matthews, 1972-1977 (Box 6, Folder 45)
  - Pacific Coast Conference on British Studies, 1972-1975 (Box 6, Folder 46)
  - PC, CBS: Santa Barbara, 1969-1979 (Box 6, Folder 47)
  - PC, CBS: Stanford, 1975-1976 (Box 6, Folder 48)
  - Correspondence: Geoffrey, 1968-1973 (Box 6, Folder 49)
  - Correspondence: Geoffrey, 1975-1979 (Box 6, Folder 50)
  - Travel arrangements, receptions, 1983 (Box 6, Folder 51)
  - Paper on Thomas Wentworth, 1971 (Box 6, Folder 52)
  - Correspondence: JBS, 1981-1983 (Box 6, Folder 53)
  - Correspondence: AHA meeting, 1987-1988 (Box 6, Folder 54)
  - Correspondence: endowment fund, 1990-1991 (Box 6, Folder 55)
  - Pacific Coast Conference on British Studies, 1987 (Box 6, Folder 56)
  - Annual meeting NACBS council: Denver, 1984-1986 (Box 6, Folder 57)
  - Miscellaneous material, 1987-1988 (Box 6, Folder 58)
  - Published materials: Spinner, Goscher, 1971-1980 (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - Expenditures, Fiscal year, 1992-1993 (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - San Francisco, costs, 1989 (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence: Nominating Committee, 1989-1990 (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - Chicago, costs, 1988-1989 (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence: miscellaneous, 1975-1983 (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence: Endowment Fund, 1983-1989 (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence: Endowment Fund, 1989-1990 (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - Correspondence: Endowment Fund, 1990 (Box 7, Folder 9)
  - Endowment Fund Committee, 1988-1991 (Box 7, Folder 10)
  - Nominating Committee, 1976 (Box 7, Folder 11)
  - Dissertation fellowship, 1989-1992 (Box 7, Folder 12)
  - Personal files: spring class, 1994 (Box 7, Folder 13)
  - Meeting minutes, 1982 (Box 7, Folder 14)
  - Correspondence: membership, 1983 (Box 7, Folder 15)
  - Snow Prize Committee, undated (Box 7, Folder 16)
  - Correspondence: election for treasurer and executive secretary, 1981-1982 (Box 7, Folder 17)
  - Correspondence: exhibits, 1981-1983 (Box 7, Folder 18)
  - Correspondence: Snow Prize, undated (Box 7, Folder 19)
  - National Coordinating Committee(NCC) fact sheets, undated (Box 7, Folder 20)
  - Correspondence: JBS, 1982-1983 (Box 7, Folder 21)
  - Correspondence: council meetings, speakers, conferences, 1981-1982 (Box 7, Folder 22)
  - Correspondence: Love Prize, undated (Box 7, Folder 23)
  - Correspondence: membership, 1983-1995 (Box 7, Folder 24)
  - Correspondence: D.C. meeting, 1983 (Box 7, Folder 25)
  - Correspondence: B.C. Prize, undated (Box 7, Folder 26)
  - By-Laws, 1981-1982 (Box 7, Folder 27)
  - Nominating Committee, 1981-1982 (Box 7, Folder 28)
  - Correspondence: miscellaneous, 1981-1983 (Box 7, Folder 29)
  - Correspondence: Zebel, Balfour, 1972-1982 (Box 7, Folder 30)
  - Correspondence: Higham, 1968-1975 (Box 7, Folder 31)
  - Correspondence: miscellaneous, 1978 (Box 7, Folder 32)
  - Correspondence, other material: Carpenter, Cole, 1970-1980 (Box 7, Folder 33)
  - Correspondence: miscellaneous, 1976 (Box 7, Folder 34)
  - Correspondence: miscellaneous, 1977 (Box 7, Folder 35)
  - Correspondence: miscellaneous, 1974-1975 (Box 7, Folder 36)
  - Pamphlets: Conference on British Studies, 1952-1956 (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - Pamphlets: Conference on British Studies, 1958-1966 (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - Pamphlets: British History Intelligencer conference, 1963-1971 (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - Pamphlets: Conference on British Studies prizes, 1960 (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - Pamphlets: British Studies research in progress, 1957-1960 (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - Pamphlets: British History Intelligencer conference, 1959-1962 (Box 8, Folder 6)
  - Intelligencer newsletter, 1954-1964 (Box 8, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence: JBS creation, 1957-1964 (Box 8, Folder 8)
  - Correspondence, papers: research in progress, 1957-1964 (Box 8, Folder 9)
  - Conference materials, 1959-1966 (Box 8, Folder 10)
  - Biographical series, 1955-1965 (Box 8, Folder 11)
  - Monograph series, 1964-1967 (Box 8, Folder 12)
  - Correspondence, 1967 (Box 8, Folder 13)
  - Correspondence, 1967 (Box 8, Folder 14)
  - Correspondence, 1967 (Box 8, Folder 15)
  - Correspondence, 1967 (Box 8, Folder 16)
  - Correspondence, 1967 (Box 8, Folder 17)
  - Correspondence: Jean Hecht, 1968 (Box 8, Folder 18)
  - Correspondence: miscellaneous, 1968-1970 (Box 8, Folder 19)
  - Archives of British History and Culture, undated (Box 8, Folder 20)
  - Correspondence: accordian file A-B, 1972 (Box 8, Folder 21)
  - Correspondence: accordian file C-F, 1972 (Box 8, Folder 22)
  - Correspondence: accordian file G-H, 1972-1973 (Box 8, Folder 23)
  - Correspondence: accordian file I-M, 1972 (Box 8, Folder 24)
  - Correspondence: accordian file N-T, 1972 (Box 8, Folder 25)
  - Correspondence: accordian file U-V, 1972 (Box 8, Folder 26)
  - Correspondence: accordian file W-Z, 1972 (Box 8, Folder 27)
  - Pamphlets, magazines: miscellaneous, 1955-1966 (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - CBS executive committee meeting, 1975 (Box 9, Folder 2)